是時候了 去召集軍團吧
Summon the legions. It is time.
我們的敵人揚言要發起進攻
Our enemy vows to attack.
你們當中有誰愿意奮起作戰
Who among you will stand and fight?
你們會死的
You will die.
這一天我已經等待很久了
Long have I awaited this day.
我向索隆宣誓效忠
I pledge my loyalty to Sauron.
我們的人已經走了一半
Half of us just left.
但還有一半選擇了留下
But half stayed.
為什么沒有選我
Why wasn't I chosen for the expedition?
我以為你要去西部
Thought you were going west.
我要先做點配得上努門諾爾人做的事
Not till I've done something worthy of Númenor.
我剛剛說服努門諾爾派出五艘船
I have just convinced Númenor to send five ships
和五百人來幫助你的人民
and 500 men to aid your people
幫你加冕為王
and place a crown upon your head.
你是在要我去一個 我發誓永遠不會回去的地方
You are asking me to go to the one place that I swore never to return.
你為什么要一直戰斗
Why do you keep fighting?
因為我停不下來
Because I cannot stop.
跟我一起去 一起拯救我們倆的種族
Come with me, and together we will redeem both our bloodlines.
我們朝東北方向行進 前往中洲
We head nor'-east. For Middle-earth.
這并不是劍 而是一種力量
It is no sword. It is a power.
你聽說過索隆嗎
Have you heard of Sauron?
我以前見過這個
I've seen this before.
這是一把鑰匙
It is a key.
敵方指揮官說過 要在這些土地上給奧克一個家
The enemy commander spoke of giving the Orcs a home in these lands.
但不管他有什么陰謀 有一點是肯定的
Whatever his design, this much is certain.
敵人知道你兒子 有他需要用來啟動計劃的東西
Our enemy knows your son has what he needs to enact it.
要多久
How long?
可能是幾個小時
Maybe hours.
指環王：力量之戒
第一季第六集
本WEB版外掛字幕由  風吹來的那片云  雙語合并
新生命
New life.
蔑視死亡
In defiance of death.
孩子們
My children,
我們經受了艱辛無數
we have endured much.
我們掙脫了枷鎖
We cast off our shackles.
越過高山和原野
Crossed mountain, field,
穿過嚴寒和荒地
frost, and fallow
直到我們腳上的血染濕了地上的泥
till our feet bloodied the dirt.
從灰色山脈到埃斐爾阿爾能
From Ered Mithrin to the Ephel Arnen,
我們都堅持下來了
we have endured.
但今晚 還有一場考驗在等著我們
Yet tonight, one more trial awaits us.
或許敵人實力很弱 而且為數不多
Our enemy may be weak, their numbers meager...
但明天黎明之前 我們當中會有一部分奧克倒下
...yet before this night is through, some of us will fall.
但如果你們這次倒下
But for the first time,
將不再是遠方大地上籍籍無名的奴隸
you do so not as unnamed slaves in far-away lands,
而是首次以兄弟的身份
but as brothers.
以兄弟姐妹的身份 在屬于我們自己的土地上倒下
As brothers and sisters in our home!
戰斗
Nampat.
Nampat! Nampat!
因為就在今夜 我們將伸出烏魯克族的鐵拳
This is the night we reach out the iron hand of the Uruk...
握緊雙拳奪回這片土地
...and close our fist around these lands.
戰斗
-Nampat!
給我搜
Search it.
全體注意 散開 把他們找出來
All of you! Fan out! Find them!
父親大人 我無意冒犯 但敢問索隆在哪里
Meaning no offense, Lord-father, but where is he?
他出什么事了
What happened to Sauron?
找不到他的絲毫蹤跡 他肯定是學聰明逃走了
Can't find tooth nor tail of him. Must've got smart and scarpered.
不會的 那個精靈就在這里
No. The Elf's here.
我聞到他的氣味了
I smell him.
遵命 父親
Yes, Father.
在這上邊
Up here!
把他拿下
Bring him down!
馬上撤出去
Get out, now!
把那扇門打開
Open that door!
快出去
Get out!
父親大人 您得立刻離開
Lord-father! You must move now!
您得離開
You must move!
這么大的火 能僥幸活下來的奧克能有多少
How many of 'em could have survived that?
我們有多少時間
How long do we have?
并沒有多少
Not long enough.
來吧 我們得把村子武裝起來
Come on, we have to make ready the village.
慢點 貝雷克 別激動
Easy, Berek. Easy, boy.
把它吊起來
Hoist it up!
我以為所有士兵都上床睡覺了
I thought all soldiers were to be abed.
請原諒我 指揮官 我只是…
Pardon me, Commander. I... I was only...
想第一個看到大陸
Hoping to get the first sight of land?
稍息
At ease.
過一會兒你就能看到了
It'll be visible to your eyes in a few moments.
難道說你已經看到了嗎
Is it visible to yours already?
大約一個小時前我就看到了
Has been for nearly an hour.
精靈的眼神真是犀利
Keen are the eyes of the Elves.
可是我卻從沒見過你
And yet, mine have not before seen you.
沒見過你舞劍也沒見過你揚帆
Swinging steel nor flying sail.
你是什么軍銜
What is your rank?
我負責清掃馬廄
Stable sweep.
不要瞧不起這種 能讓人學會謙遜的勞苦工作
Despise not the labor which humbles the heart.
對于整個王國來說 滿招損謙受益
Humility has saved entire kingdoms the proud have all but led to ruin.
我加入遠征軍 可不是為了來學習謙遜的 指揮官
I did not join this expedition to be humbled, Commander.
那你加入的目的是什么 士兵
Then for what did you join, soldier?
我只是想離開
I was just trying to get away.
盡可能遠離那個地方
As far as I could from that place.
努門諾爾嗎
Númenor?
不是努門諾爾
It's not Númenor.
反正不是真正的努門諾爾
Not the real Númenor, anyway.
真正的努門諾爾根本沒存在過
If it ever existed.
它存在過
It existed.
而且仍然存在…
It exists still...
哪怕只存在于最下層的 馬廄清潔工心里
If only in the heart of the lowliest stable sweep.
我叫伊熙爾杜
It's Isildur.
我早該看出來
I might have known.
你長得像你父親
You have the look of your father.
人們總說我長得更像我母親
I was always told I look more like my mother.
士兵
Soldier.
船長
Captain.
他母親…
His mother...
她出什么事了
What happened to her?
很奇怪
It is strange.
我大半輩子 望向東方都是見旭日從海面上升起
Most of my life, I've looked east to see the Sun rise over the sea.
望向西方見夕陽落到地平線下
And west to see it set over the land.
雖然我們正駛向黎明 但對我而言
We're sailing into the dawn, and yet, to me,
感覺卻像夜幕即將降臨
it feels like the coming of night.
她是淹死的
She drowned.
已經看到陸地了 陛下
Land has been sighted, Your Majesty.
我們多久才能拋錨停泊
How long before we make anchor?
要航行一整天才能進入山區
It's a full day's sail into the mountains.
從那里出發 要向東再騎一天才能進入山谷
And from there, another day's ride east into the vale.
給其他船發信號
Signal the other ships.
告訴他們盡可能加快速度
Tell them to make all possible haste.
以我們的能力無法毀掉它
It is beyond our skill to destroy.
你要把它藏在哪
Where will you hide it?
不能讓任何人知道
No one must know.
就連你也不行
Not even you.
我們已經發現了敵人
Our enemy has been sighted.
上一次我們活了下來
We survived them before.
這次我們也必將戰勝敵人
Now we must do so again.
今晚
Tonight.
我們的位置很有利
Our position gives us an advantage.
但要想利用這個優勢 必須把敵人引到近處
But to use it, we must draw the enemy in close.
我們必須等到所有奧克
We must wait until every last Orc
跨過那座橋之后 再發起進攻
has crossed that bridge to spring our attack.
這將會考驗你們的勇氣
This will test your nerve.
放馬過來吧
Let it.
所有無法戰斗的人員將在里邊駐守
All who cannot fight will be barricaded inside.
這里將是我們的要塞和撤退據點
This is to be our keep. Our fallback point.
大家都要鼓起勇氣
-Take heart. All of you.
我見過許多軍隊以少勝多
I have seen smaller armies defeat greater foes.
太陽很快就要落山了
Soon, the sun will set.
我向你們保證 只要守好自己的崗位 就能見到明天的日出
Do your part, and I swear to you, you shall see it rise again.
-你們相信嗎  -相信
-Do you believe it? -Aye.
-Do you believe it? -Aye!
各就各位
To your positions.
那我呢
What about me?
你去小酒館
Tavern.
傷員和兒童才去小酒館 我可以戰斗
Tavern's for wounded and children. I can fight.
我知道你可以
I know you can.
所以我才要你去那里 保護無法戰斗的人
Which is why I need you in there, protecting those who cannot.
來吧
Come.
我小時候經常會做各種噩夢 你記得嗎
Remember when I was little... When I used to have bad dreams?
我記得
I remember.
還記得你是怎么安慰我的嗎
You remember what you used to say?
就是你在黑暗中抱著我說的那番話
When you would hold me in the dark?
現在能再說給我聽嗎
Would you say it to me now?
“魔影終究只是渺小之物 且會逝去
"In the end, this shadow is but a small and passing thing.
“而在魔影無法觸及之處
"There is light and high beauty
“光明與崇高之美永存
"forever beyond its reach.
“去尋找光明吧…
"Find the light...
“如此魔影便永遠不得臨身”
"And the shadow will not find you."
再見 媽媽
Farewell, Mother.
準備好了嗎
Are you ready?
沒有 你呢
No. Are you?
阿爾費林種子…
The alfirin seeds...
這是精靈的一項傳統
It is a tradition among Elves.
每逢戰爭開始之前 種下一顆阿爾費林種子
Before the battle begins, plant one.
新生命 蔑視死亡
New life, in defiance of death?
精靈族相信 有一位維拉
It is believed that one of the Valar
會照看生長的植物…
watches over growing things...
以及植物的播種者
And those who tend them.
其余的種子…
The rest...
我們等戰爭結束后再來種
we shall plant after the battle is over.
種在一個新花園里
In a new garden.
你和我
You and I.
還有希奧
And Theo.
我們一起種
Together.
一言為定
Promise me.
他們來了
-They're here.
我的天…
Oh, dear...
那群蠢貨沒打中我們
The bleeding fools missed us.
來吧
Come on!
他們正朝小酒館走去
They're headed for the tavern.
-為南方大地而戰  -為南方大地而戰
-Fight for the Southlands! -Fight for the Southlands!
這片土地是我們的
The land is ours!
非常勇敢啊 精靈 很勇敢
More than a bit brave, Elf. More than a bit.
布隆溫
Bronwyn.
我們剛才是在與自己人戰斗
We were fighting our own.
你們以為我們會白白收留他們
Thought we'd take 'em in for nothin'?
必須付出代價…
Had to pay the toll...
你們所有人都要付出代價
And now, all of you will.
特雷德威爾
Tredwill!
媽媽
Mother!
所有人 躲進要塞
Everyone, to the keep!
快走
Go! Go!
進小酒館里
Into the tavern!
小酒館
The tavern!
所有人
All of you!
快走
Go!
放桌子上
-The table!
快點
-Hurry!
媽媽
-Mother. Mother.
先救他
Help him first.
不要啊
No.
我們會救你的
We will help you.
媽媽
Mother.
希奧…
Theo...
你必須趕快止血
You'll have to stem the bleeding.
我不會…
I... I don't think I...
要么你來止血 要么我就會死 你明白嗎
Either you're gonna do this or I'm gonna die. Do you understand?
希奧
Theo.
媽媽 你做好準備
Mother, prepare yourself.
對不起
I am sorry.
用力壓住傷口
Put pressure on the wound.
燒…
Burn...
她失血過多 身體發冷
She's cold. She's lost too much blood.
不要
No. No. No.
她說了：“燒”
She's saying "burn."
阿爾費林種子 我們必須用火把止住傷口出血
The alfirin seeds. We have to seal the wound with fire.
給我拿一些點燃的木頭過來 快
Bring me some burning wood. Hurry!
現在
Now.
就是現在
現在換這邊
Now this side.
繼續
Go on.
夠了
That's enough.
布隆溫
Bronwyn?
-媽媽  -布隆溫
-Mother? -Bronwyn?
醒醒 媽媽
Wake up! Mother!
戰斗
Nampat!
- 踢他們的后背 - 戰斗
-Kick 'em in the back! -Nampat!
坐下
-Sit down!
我要找的東西
What I seek.
把它交給我
Give it to me.
先把他們放了
Let them go.
然后我才會考慮
I will consider it.
何苦為了這么點小東西 搭上他們的性命
Why sacrifice their lives for such a little thing?
下一個是那個女人
The woman next.
不要
No!
-等等  -希奧
-Wait! -Theo!
在這下邊
It's under here.
不要
No.
希奧
Theo!
對不起
I'm sorry.
沃德雷格 我有個任務要交給你
Waldreg, I have a task for you.
他們全都得死
They all must die.
安塔摩
Ontamo!
去吧
Go.
Hyah!
父親
Father!
-我沒事 -我以為你…
-I'm all right. -I thought you...
我沒事的 伊熙爾杜
I'm all right, Isil.
士兵
Soldier.
他們的指揮官呢
Their commander?
他手上的東西…
The item he possesses...
絕對不能讓他帶走
He must not escape with it.
那是誰
Who is that?
北征軍的指揮官
Commander of the Northern Armies.
加拉德瑞爾
Galadriel.
跑快點
Noro lim!
快
Go!
你記得我嗎
You remember me?
不記得
No.
住手
Stop!
我們需要留他一命
We need him alive.
我需要留他一命
I need him alive.
你不知道他干過什么事
You don't know what he did.
我傷害過你愛的人嗎
Did I cause someone you love pain?
是個女人嗎
A woman?
或許是個孩子
Perhaps a child?
閉嘴
Eat your tongue.
哈爾布蘭德 把劍放下
Halbrand, put it down.
區區復仇遠遠無法讓人滿足
One cannot satisfy thirst by drinking sea water.
那么 你覺得怎么樣
So, what do you think?
我喜歡這些山
I like the mountains.
你馬上就能近距離看這些山了
You're about to get a closer look at them.
指揮官加拉德瑞爾正在組建一支軍隊
Commander Galadriel's putting together a company
追蹤逃走的奧克
to track down the Orcs that escaped,
我苦口婆心才為我們倆求得位置
and I managed to wheedle the pair of us a spot.
那安塔摩呢
What about Ontamo?
我想我可能會 在這里待一陣子 幫幫這些人
I think I might stay here for a while. Lend these folk a hand.
-這周的戰爭看夠了  -恐怕是一輩子的戰爭都看夠了
-Seen enough battle for a week? -More like a whole lifetime.
這支軍隊什么時候出發
This company, when's it set out?
還不確定 要等加拉德瑞爾先處理完阿達爾
Don't know for certain. Not till she's done with him.
我小的時候 聽過很多精靈被魔茍斯帶走的故事
When I was a child, I heard stories of Elves taken by Morgoth.
那些精靈被折磨 被扭曲
Tortured. Twisted.
他們被改造為 一種新的 被摧殘的生命形式
Made into a new and ruined form of life.
你就是其中一員吧
You are one of them, are you not?
魔里昂多
The Moriondor.
黑暗之子
The Sons of the Dark.
第一批奧克
The first Orcs.
烏魯克族
Uruk.
我們更喜歡自稱“烏魯克族”
We prefer "Uruk."
就連魔里昂多也是聽令于主人的
Even Moriondor take orders from a master.
我要找你的主人
And I seek yours.
他在哪
Where is he?
索隆在哪
Where is Sauron?
或許我們應該讓囚犯們曬曬太陽
Perhaps we should bring our prisoners into the sunlight.
魔茍斯戰敗后
After Morgoth's defeat,
你們稱之為索隆的那一位…
the one you call Sauron...
致力于“治愈”中洲
Devoted himself to healing Middle-earth,
將被毀壞的土地 以完美的秩序重新聚攏在一起
bringing its ruined lands together in perfect order.
他試圖打造一種力量
He sought to craft a power
并非來源于肉體…
not of the flesh...
而是讓肉體受控于它
But over flesh.
一種不可見世界的力量
A power of the Unseen World.
他說服盡可能多的人隨他向北行進
He bid as many as he could to follow him far north.
但雖然他竭盡所能…
But try as he might...
他還是缺少一樣東西
Something was missing.
那就是黑暗知識的影子
A shadow of dark knowledge
一直隱藏著 就是不讓他找到
that kept itself hidden, even from him.
哪怕他在求索的過程中 手上已經沾滿無數鮮血
No matter how much blood he spilt in its pursuit.
對我來說…
Mmm. For my part...
為了幫助他實現愿望 我已經犧牲了足夠多的孩子
I sacrificed enough of my children for his aspirations.
我把索隆撕碎了
I split him open.
我殺了他
I killed Sauron.
我不信你
I do not believe you.
你的整支軍隊都殺不掉索隆
You cannot believe an Uruk could do that
你當然不信一個烏魯克就能做到
which your entire army could not.
我不相信你是這支軍隊唯一的主人
I cannot believe that you are this army's only master.
我的孩子們沒有主人
My children have no master.
他們不是孩子 是奴隸
They are not children, they are slaves.
但他們每一個都有姓名 有內心
But each one has a name. A heart. A heart.
-由魔茍斯創造的內心 -我們都出自獨一之神的手
-A heart created by Morgoth. -We are creations of The One,
出自秘火的主宰 跟你一樣
Master of the Secret Fire, the same as you.
他們也值得擁有生命之息
As worthy of the breath of life,
也同樣值得擁有家園
and just as worthy of a home.
很快…
Soon...
這片土地將會是我們的 到時候你就會明白
This land will be ours. Then, you will understand.
并不是
No.
你族群的存在就是個錯誤
Your kind was a mistake.
一群拙劣的仿制品
Made in mockery.
哪怕要花上一整個紀元 我也會發誓要將你們斬草除根
And even if it takes me all of this Age, I vow to eradicate every last one of you.
但我會讓你活著
But you shall be kept alive,
好讓你見證那一天
so that one day,
到時候我會用匕首刺入你中毒的心臟
before I drive my dagger into your poisoned heart,
我會在你尖尖的耳朵旁低語
I will whisper in your piked ear
你的后代已經死絕了
that all your offspring are dead
你種族的禍根將以你為終結
and the scourge of your kind ends with you.
看來我不是唯一一個還活著
It would seem I'm not the only Elf alive
但已經被黑暗所改變的精靈
who has been transformed by darkness.
也許你苦苦尋找的魔茍斯繼任者
Perhaps your search for Morgoth's successor
會在你的鏡子里尋見
should have ended in your own mirror.
也許我應該先殺了你 你這個奧克的奴隸販子
Perhaps I shall begin by killing you, you slavering Orc.
加拉德瑞爾
Galadriel.
烏魯克…
Uruk.
你是誰
Who are you?
謝謝你…
Thank you...
把我拉了回來
For pulling me back.
早前是你先把我拉了回來
Was you, pulled me back first.
不管他對你做了什么
Whatever it was he did to you,
也不管你做了什么…
and whatever it was you did...
都要放下
Be free of it.
我從不相信我能放下…
I never believed I could be...
直到今天
Until today.
與你并肩作戰 我…
Fighting at your side, I...
我感覺…
I felt...
如果我能抓住這種感覺
If I could just hold on to that feeling,
時刻保留在我身邊
keep it with me always,
并將它深深刻入我的靈魂 那么我…
bind it to my very being, then I...
我也感覺到了
I felt it, too.
哈爾布蘭德大人 攝政女王想見您
-Lord Halbrand. The Queen Regent wishes to see you.
攝政女王
Queen Regent.
我欠你的…你讓我的人民得以幸存
What I owe you... My people are alive because of you.
按照我的理解 他們之所以能活著是因為你
As I understand it, they're alive because of you.
我可沒想過要扛起這份重擔
A burden I never sought to take up.
只有極少數最優秀的領袖 才能扛此重任
Few of the finest leaders do.
但如果你想減輕這份負擔
But if you would like some relief in carrying it,
我也許能幫上忙
I may be able to help.
陛下 您找我
You called for me, Your Majesty?
布隆溫…
Bronwyn...
這位是哈爾布蘭德大人
This is Lord Halbrand.
布隆溫
Bronwyn.
是真的嗎  你就是他們承諾給我們的那位國王
Is it true? Are you the king we were promised?
是的
Yes.
所有人致敬
All hail!
向南方大地真正的國王致敬
All hail to the true King of the Southlands!
這片土地上的人們 已經等待這一刻很久了
The men of these lands have awaited this moment a long time.
肯定沒有精靈等得久
Not nearly so long as the Elves.
別折磨自己了
Do not torment yourself.
換做別人 很多人也會做同樣的選擇
Many might have done the same in your place.
你不明白
You don't understand.
我感到的不僅僅是內疚
It's not just guilt I feel.
還有一種失去感
It's loss.
失去感
Loss?
當它在我手中時
When it was in my hands,
我感覺…
I felt...
非常強大
Powerful.
那就擺脫掉它
Then rid yourself of it.
一勞永逸
Once and for all.
怎么擺脫
How?
交給努門諾爾
Give it to Númenor.
讓他們在返航回家的途中扔進海里
To toss into the sea on their voyage home.
放輕松 貝雷克
-Easy. Berek, easy.
劃傷了一點而已 你沒事的
It's just a scratch. You're okay.
嘿…貝雷克
Hey, hey, hey. Berek.
小心點
-Careful.
幫幫忙
Athae...
冷靜下來
no ídhui hí.
你是怎么做到的
How did you do that?
困擾它的并不是它身上的疼痛…
It's not his pain that's bothering him...
而是騎手的疼痛
But that of his rider.
我不覺得痛啊
-I'm not in pain.
當西方之地努門諾爾的馬匹 進入戰場時
When a horse of Westernesse rides into battle,
它會與騎乘的戰士 形成一種牢不可破的紐帶
he forms an unbreakable bond with the soldier he bears.
隨著時間的推移 人馬合一
In time, they become as one.
甚至能夠了解彼此的內心深處
Even knowing the innermost feelings of each other's heart.
-你了解它的感受  -不了解
-You know his feelings? -No.
但它了解你的
He knows yours.
你是從哪里學到這些的
Where did you learn all this?
從你媽媽那里
From your mother.
你能教我嗎
Think you could teach me?
烏頓…
Ud?n... Ud?n. Ud?n.
快找掩護
Take shelter!
女王
The Queen!
貝雷克
Berek!
維藍迪爾
Valandil!
翻過墻去
Over the wall!
-希奧  -希奧
-Theo! -Theo!
字幕翻譯：腐哥
創意監督 羅婷婷